Divyam Rana

Programmer and Researcher



divyamrana@gmail.com



+1 (858) 999-6405



+91 7011219944



linkedin.com/in/divyamrana

Education

University of California, San Diego, Anticipated: 2023 Mathematics and Computer Science

Minor: Data Science GPA 3.872/4.000

Amity International School, Saket, New Delhi, INDIA High School

Percentage: 92.2%

CBSE: Physics, Chemistry, Mathematics, Computer

Science, English

Strengths

Research

Analytical skills

Technical Acumen

Data visualization

Business Acumen

Collaborative Team Player

Effective Communication

Adaptability

Handling pressure

Reference

Adalbert Gerald Soosai Raj Assistant Teaching Professor, University of California, San Diego

Email: gerald@eng.ucsd.edu

Profile Summary

I am a dedicated and motivated programmer and researcher with passion for software development. I find myself particularly interested in learning and interacting with technologies and implementing my current knowledge base on the same. I am a problem-solver and enjoy working in an environment which challenges me every day and enables me to grow and push my boundaries.

Experience

Researcher, University of California, San Diego June 2020 – Present

- Associated with the Computer Science Education Lab (CSEd) where we are analyzing the trends of native and non-native English speakers in lower division computer science courses.
- Paper titled 'A Quantitative Analysis of Lecture Videos and Student Feedback on Static Code Examples and Live Coding: A Case Study' published in proceedings of the 23rd Australasian Computing Education Conference (ACE) 2021.

Quarterly Project, IEEE, University of California, San Diego January 2020 – March 2020

 Worked on developing an Android app AutoGradeee which is a studentcentered android application which helps in proper management of the student's courses. It helps determining what marks do the students need to get in order to get the desired grade, how much work they should put in on average, how to effectively utilize time etc.

Intern, Star Mobileoid2 Technologies Pvt Ltd, INDIA June 2018 – September 2018

- Tested mobile applications.
- Assisted in development of the applications for the clients.

Related Skills and Activities

- Relevant Coursework: Data Structures, Object oriented programming, Discrete Mathematics, Algorithm design and analysis, Software tools and techniques, Linear Algebra, Advanced Data Structures, Statistical Methods
- Programming Languages

\sim	1
()	Java
\sim	Juva

O C

O C++

 \circ R

O Python

O HTML and CSS

- ARM (intermediate)
- Training in progress about neural networks and machine learning with TensorFlow API
- Participated in HARD hackathon, SD Hacks, ACM Coding competition.